Silicon,
the foundation of modern technology.
Every transistor placed with purpose.
[music]
Every watt wrestled from physics. Where
every instruction set earns its right to
execute.
This is how performance gets driven, how
efficiency gets built, how intelligence
acts, not just [music] answers.
Our future is with ecosystems.
Shaped by architecture.
Capable of connecting technologies,
tools, and partners. Powerful enough to
execute. Efficient enough to scale.
Familiar enough to build with speed.
Tomorrow, it's about the progress we
scale through open platforms, shared
standards, and partnerships amplifying
each other's strengths. A unified
architecture engineered for systems. The
next chapter is being written in silicon
with our engineering at its heart. Built
different, built together, built on
Intel.
And now, ladies and gentlemen, please
give a warm welcome to the CEO of Intel,
Luan.
Intel computer
uh
steps.
Uh this is the elephant mountain. And so
1,000 step to 184 meter and so I
survived
[applause]
and I came down with one piece. So I'm
here. So but if I walk a little bit
slower then you know uh I'm exhausted.
But anyway it's a beautiful view. I mean
highly recommend all of you to do that.
Yep. I think first of all I think uh
delighted to be here and uh this is an
important event and then I'd like to uh
get started
and about
nearly six decades ago a group of
brilliant and highly motivated engineers
and venture capitalists
uh including Rock Don Valentine and many
others if Now companies like Intel,
Apple and others broadly set the motion
the largest economic known to mankind uh
create what became known as Silicon
Valley and uh this is a very exciting
time and that is a very same ambition
and mindset with the semiconductors make
across the ocean. that sparked the
creation of Silicon Island right here in
Taiwan. And I have been very fortunate
to associate with the creation of
semiconductor industry in Taiwan 40
years ago
uh because uh 40 years ago uh Minister
KT Lee Leeing
uh invite me to lay the foundation of
venture capital concept in Taiwan. It's
a very new concept and uh you know you
keep people put money with you and they
play the money and then you share the
profit of 20%. But you don't share 20%
of the losses. So this is a very unique
uh venture capital concept but I managed
to do that and then with the help of
Minister KT Lee and then development
fund and I set up my venture fund and
about the same time you know uh uh
Maurice Chang uh from TI came back to E3
and then uh then set up the TSMC. So
it's a very exciting time that I'm being
involved in this whole science park and
uh Shinto science park and the
foundation of become the silicon island
and so I really see the benefit of you
know uh from OEM ODM from design to
manufacturing
is all here in Taiwan. Taiwan PC
ecosystem has played a critical role uh
in Intel growth and success. I in fact
last year I was here uh to celebrate
Intel 40th anniversary in Taiwan. I want
to thank all of the suppliers,
partners and customers for 40 years of
partnership with Intel. As partnership
continue to grow.
Thank you. [applause]
As partnership continue to grow and uh
stronger every year.
It had been the year since I stepped in
uh the role of Intel CEO to be more
precise 14 months uh to being CEO of
Intel and it may be the first CEO can
speak Mandarin
[applause]
and in fact couple of uh customer of
Taiwan very important partner for us is
that lio also So very unusual if a CEO
can drink liquor with us
but anyway it's I'm part of this
community uh execution has always always
at the top of my list to do so we had to
bring focus back to the core uh at our
heart Intel is a engineering company and
that's what I decided from day one I
came to become CEO of Intel I I have all
the engineering report to me so they're
understanding to really drive the
engineering drive success in engineering
uh performance. Our customer and
partners are always uh you know already
seen a shift uh in the Intel showed up.
We are just getting started and so stay
tuned. We have a journey in front of us.
opportunity ahead is enormous and our
job is to stay focused, execute and
deliver.
Every year Intel ship hundred millions
of uh hundreds and millions of uh SOC
orchestrating silicon across every
industry working tightly with our
partners ecosystem across each layer of
the stack
from silicon to SOC to system and to
software. This generates trillions of
dollars in value across four core
compute ecosystem.
First personal computers,
second edge agentic AI and later
physical AI, third foundational data
centers
and finally emerging intelligence
centers that will power digital agents
of the future. Each of these ecosystem
represent generational opportunity
and increasingly each of these will need
purpose-built CPU,
GPU and A6 solutions cers for specific
workloads and application. The silicon
we are building now
will be for human use and the digital
agent use.
Let us begin with the ecosystem that
started all to talk more about the PC
ecosystem. Please join me to welcome to
stage our new leaders for client compute
and physical AI, Alex
>> [applause]
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Lupu.
Little story about me. The first time I
came to Taiwan was the year 1990
and I was fresh out of school, first
job, first international trip
and I came right here in Taipei.
And I quickly realized even back then
that
you know this the the desire to grow uh
the mindset of win-win and cooperation
is all over all of our customers and our
partners here in Taiwan. And now
forward the clock 36 years I'm here in
my first international trip with all the
great people here at Intel. And where do
I come? Right here to Taipei.
Thank you. [applause]
I can't wait to plan and build the
future with you guys. So, let's get
started. We have a lot to cover.
Intel has continuously increased the
pace of progress across all PC segments.
Workstations, desktops, creators,
gamers, premium and mainstream laptops,
every major segment. Every major segment
is driven by an Intel system solution.
With that vast coverage in mind,
we're adding another dimension to scale
these products even more effectively.
The Intel 18A process is now at full
scale.
We have a full lineup of products with
hundreds of design wins to prove that.
At CES,
we launched the Core Ultra Series 3,
Intel's first product built on 18A
process technology.
It's setting a new standard for premium
mobile performance and battery life.
The Ultra Series 3 enables great user
experiences across any tasks
with a very fast response CPU,
a highly improved GPU,
low power processing NPU, and the latest
multimedia capabilities.
It's a perfect blend of IP performance
and power for any AI and agentic
experience.
It's allowing us to lead the way to
transform every PC, every PC to an
agentic capable platform.
Today,
more than 300 designs are shipping
across consumer and commercial segments,
over 300.
And to scale these capabilities even
further, we've taken the latest core
ultra IPs and specifically tailored them
for the mainstream market.
The result, the Intel Core Series 3
introduced in April. Let me repeat, we
just introduced this in April and it's
already scaled up to 70 plus designs.
That brings Thank you. [applause]
Thank you.
That brings the total series lineup to
nearly 400 designs in just a few short
months. Now, that is massive scale.
Let's look at some of the capabilities
of the Core Series 3. And we can start
with battery life. You know, I can go
over these numbers here that are printed
and I can talk about how we measure them
and things like that, but I I have a
question for you guys. How long is your
day? 10 hours, 12 hours, 14 hours,
or more like us at Intel.
But the great user experience is if your
PC lasts longer than your workday. And
that's exactly what we're delivering in
all segments.
And we support ample number of ports for
all of your connectivity needs, unlike
some of our competitors who only have
one USBC interface. But I'll let you be
the judge of that one. Yeah.
[applause]
The goal of this uh uh Core Series 3 is
to bring premium feel and experiences to
incredibly thin form factors for
mainstream PCs.
And you know, you don't have to take my
word for it. You can look at this wall
of incredibly designed, sleek PCs that
are here, and all of it is thanks to
you, our partners, and our customers. We
couldn't have done it without you. So,
please, a round of applause. [applause]
Isn't it awesome? Super light, super
thin, really great.
Okay. Now, the next proof is scaling 18A
IP into growing markets.
And the fastest growing portion of the
PC market is the handheld gaming. Let's
take a look.
>> [music]
>> Are you killing it? Heat. Heat.
[music]
[applause]
>> [applause]
>> This is the ARC G3.
I think a beautiful chip, more beautiful
than what was presented yesterday at a
keynote.
[applause]
Okay.
The G3 is derived from the Core Ultra
Series 3 and the ARC G3 is a tuned
high-erformance GPU specifically for
handheld gaming and it's providing great
battery life.
The performance tested across multiple
games is consistent and stable versus
competition.
We are more than 40% faster, 40% faster,
and at the same performance, we're half
the power.
And on top of that, we're running all
AAA games at 1080p resolution, many of
them above 120 frames per second. Now,
that is giving gamers a great user
experience.
All of these devices will be available
late later this month, and is just the
beginning. We're going to have plenty
more designs coming throughout the year.
Thank you. [applause] Thank you.
Okay, it is indeed true that Intel has a
leading lineup of processors and with
the ver versatility of the ATNA process
technology, our newest offerings, we're
bringing powerful performance and
efficiency to scale across the breadth
of premium mainstream and handheld
gaming segments.
These same fundamentals, the same IP,
the same capabilities can deliver far
beyond the PC ecosystem.
The demand for our processors at the
edge has been booming.
As you've seen, we've already taken
existing product lines and pivoted them
into adjacent markets, enabling our
customers to grow their businesses.
Now, the edge is demanding the latest
products from Intel. And that's why this
year, we're taking our latest series 3
products into the edge business with
over 130 designs in multiple verticals.
For largecale edge business, our
customers need the best technology and
chipsets, easy to use reference designs,
and appropriate software stacks.
And at Intel, we've done all of that.
We have over 4,000 edge ecosystem
partners deploying into such verticals
such as manufacturing, robotics, retail,
and many more.
For those of you here at Computex, you
can see some of that at the pavilion.
Given that capability, given the IP,
given the chipsets, given the scale that
we have, there's a massive opportunity
ahead of us across many segments of
physical AI.
It's projected to be a 25 trillion
market by 2050, and it will leverage all
of our scale in the PC ecosystem.
Physical AI form factors will take shape
across key industries, as you see behind
me.
We will continue growing these markets
with the same strategy of leading IP and
chipsets, complete reference platforms
of enduser hardware and applicable
software stacks, enabling our customers
to expand into new physical AI form
factors and applications.
And indeed, this will be our future.
Now, back to you, Liipu. Thank you.
[applause]
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Uh thanks, Alex.
AI is profoundly impacting the way we
use our devices.
A major focus area for us is the use of
AI on device.
Together with partners, we are at the
forefront of advancing intelligence.
To tell you more about it, let me
welcome on stage my close friend and
founder CEO of Perplexity, Aravvin.
[applause]
[music]
Well, Aravvin, welcome. You and I have
been talking about hybrid compute for a
while. The reason why are clear
you know the privacy cost performance
and let's talk about how to make this
work. Yeah. So in February we launched
perplexity computer. Computer is an AI
operating system. It creates a team of
agents,
uses up to 20 different AI models, and
it orchestrates across models, tools,
and files in one single system.
The agent harness inside computer is
model agnostic,
perfectly balancing intelligence,
accuracy, privacy, and cost is the
orchestration problem it solves. And so
this allows you to run smaller models
locally on the Intel Core Ultra Series 3
GPU. And so for the first time ever, we
work together to create hybrid aenic
inference. And so what we are showing
today is just the start. Hybrid agenic
inference is how we maximize token value
per watt per user.
>> So should we show them how it works?
>> Yep.
>> All right. So here it is.
Let's say I'm an associate at a private
equity firm and u I'm working on
something that has a confidential
project code name project falcon. Here's
the query.
So, think of it as me trying to
understand if a certain private company
is worth $1.1 billion and I'm feeding it
confidential deal materials.
The work begins on the laptop. It sees
that project falcon has private dealroom
files and an NDA, a local leverage
buyout financial model, a whiteboard
diagram and bilingual transcripts that
are very confidential. You don't want
these materials to be shipped to the
server. So what the local model does on
the core ultra series 3 is it first
decides this is all very important work
and shouldn't be sent to the server. It
reads the files classifies what is
sensitive and what is not and then
computer decides what should leave the
device and what shouldn't and each of
these things is done with local AI.
The orchestrator can spin up additional
agents as necessary.
And so if you need a research agent to
bring in outside file materials against
local model without exposing any private
files, that's what you want in the
hybrid system. And so computer arc acts
as one single system, brings all inputs
and outputs together. And so let's
actually skip and see what the actual
result would be.
All right. So, the result is a document,
a research report and sporting data. And
it's been created by agents on large
cloud-based models keeping your
sensitive information only on your
device. And so all your local device
models will take care of the private
files and the server side models will
take care of other things. true hybrid
inference orchestration.
>> This is the architecture we both believe
in and the future is more compute in the
data center and more compute on the
local machine.
>> And so I think of this as a big
milestone for engineering on both the
agent harness AI side as well as the
chip side. And so um it's been really
fun to partner with you and Intel on
this. So thank you so much Libu.
>> Definitely. Thank you Aravvin and
looking forward to continue partnership.
Thank you. [applause]
>> We talk a lot about the exciting new
developments in the PC edge and physical
AI space. I want to take a few minutes
to talk about the foundational IP that
power all these advancements.
Let us talk about x86.
When most people think of generalpurpose
computing, they think x86
and that is a good reason for that. X86
is architecture that has power data
center for nearly five decades
and the leadership continues.
uh according to the IDC expect eight out
of the 10 servers installed through 2030
to be x86based
powering modern computing from
foundational to emerging intelligent use
cases.
Intel pioneer most of the breakthrough
architectural innovation
that have enhanced 886 over the last
four decades starting with the 8086
that become the foundation of modern
computing.
Uh if you can see the chart today we
have two flagship CPU cores
pores and ECores.
One optimized for performance,
one the others is for efficiency.
These are Intel most advanced CPU cores
with the accelerator building
built in spec uh specifically for
foundational workloads like security.
Our x86 cores power our PC client edge
portfolio and also power our data center
and AI portfolio.
Under my leadership, we are committed to
building the best CPU cores in the world
and we will enhance ensure that the most
compute intensive workload run best on
886 x86.
Next, let us talk. Thank you.
Now let us talk about how x86 is
enabling foundational data centers.
To tell you more about it, let me invite
on to the stage Kavoke.
[applause]
[music]
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, Libu.
Wow. It's so great to be here. uh
specifically in this point in our
history, global history, collective
history and be at Computex with a blue
badge. So I'm very happy, I'm very
humbled to be here to share with you
some of the innovations that we have. So
uh let's [snorts] talk a bit about uh
see what this AI thing is about. So when
we say foundational,
we mean the workloads that keep the
world running. So currently we have data
centers and there's a number of items
and workloads and entities that run on
these data centers. So uh for example we
have 5G networks that uh keep us
connected. We have databases that keep
our data safe. We have cloud services
that power our daily lives. So we expect
and demand for these workloads to to
grow in size and capacity between uh now
and 2030 from 80 gawatt to about 100
gawatt and uh yeah most of you involved
in this uh domain understand the the the
extent of this type of an expansion.
These workloads are broad. They are
mission critical. So attention special
attention has to be taken uh when
running them but [clears throat] also
they require performance, efficiency,
security and resiliency. And we can't
emphasize enough uh all these four
factors.
That is why we are excited to have Intel
Xeon 6 Plus introduced at Computex this
week.
It has 288 eores, a massive 576 megabyte
of L3 cache
built with our Intel 18A technology. And
we can't emphasize enough the the value
of uh Intel technology that brings to
data center products. But most
importantly, it delivers
efficiency and density which enables our
partners to save uh very precious real
estate, have more compact servers and
the racks.
So this is a leadership compute for the
next era of cloud and network
infrastructure.
So Zeon 6 Plus launches with the
strength of our ecosystem that's been
built over decades and decades of data
center development both from a hardware
but also from a software and
infrastructure perspective.
Moreover, our ODM partners are bringing
Zeon 6 plus solutions to the market
today.
So these range from full rack scale
deployments to server level designs.
Xeon 6 Plus joins
our lineup of data center processors
next to our already launch Xeon 6 based
on peores.
Both of these uh category and class of
uh solutions delivers new performance
and choice for all the enterprises whose
infrastructure backbone is built on x86
and zeon.
This is critical for enterprises that
need to increasingly balance preparing
for AI workloads but at the same time
running their day-to-day mission
critical applications.
So let's switch gears and talk about how
Intel was certifying the deployment of
intelligence at scale.
It's undeniable that enterprise
infrastructure today will have to evolve
to keep up with the AI demand.
Recent research forecasts that AI
inference workloads are expected to
become 40% of all data center power
demand and much more than uh they are
today.
So we have these two paradigms where we
have the foundational data centers keep
on running their traditional workloads
but at the same time they have to figure
out ways of building their
infrastructures to serve intelligence at
scale and this is where Intel and Xeon 6
plus come in.
Now up to now training split the data
center into two. So on one hand we have
CPUled enterprise infrastructure
and the other hand we have GPU heavy AI
factories and that was very clear divide
for a while right and we've all been
accustomed to that uh that reality
but as agentic AI moves into real
workflows data tools governance the
needs change the next wave is not just
about training models it is about
putting AI to work so let's look at why
Agentic AI changes the infrastructure
equation.
The way AI inference works is
straightforward. We take a prompt, it
gets fed into an LLM where it spends
most time reasoning about the prompt. I
we've all seen this. We've done this
thousands of times and out comes an
answer.
In this case, a lot of time is spent
computing the large language model which
is mostly GPU and compute intensive.
Now the way agentic AI works is
radically different. It's given goals
rather than prompts. So we all seen the
uh the different types of loop that
people are running on this agentic AI.
It's also very iterative in nature but
also prompted by automation
and thinking, planning, acting and
reflecting are a natural way of these
agents interacting with us.
as it works, it uses tools, reads and
writes files, checks rules and other
aspect that were, you know, in the
traditional realm of CPUs and x86.
And then for each step, the type of
underlying
compute needs is very different and
we'll show that in a bit.
This is particularly important as agents
scale up their work spawning new agents
that work concurrently and the category
and the complexity of agents are going
to be very different depending on the
complexity of the work.
That's the main reason that there's such
a rapid increase in CPU demand for
Aentic AI. The CPU orchestrates the
show.
Now what we're seeing is we're also
seeing the balance and the ratio of uh
one CPU to 8GPU and more is uh is coming
much closer to parity. So let's take a
look at the real example. John, thanks
Kavorg. You talked about how Agentic AI
is changing the compute requirements.
Let's take a look at a real example. I
have a traditional AI inference setup on
the lefth hand side of the screen. Let's
send a request. Write a Python function
that calls an OpenAI compatible chat
completions API. The model gets the
response, generates code, and sends the
request back. Take a look at the slider
on the top of the screen. GPU dominates
nearly 7 to1 GPU heavy.
In contrast, let's take a look at an
agentic AI system. Across the top, look
at the pipeline stages. Green is GPU
work. Blue is CPU work. Linting is
happening on our Xeon 6 plus processor
with effic efficiency cores. Web fetch
and compile is happening on our Xeon 6
performance cores
and unit testing is coming back and
running on our Xeon 6 plus effic
efficiency cores.
The right class CPU for each stage of
the pipeline. Take a look at the slider
across the top again. We're near par but
CPU heavy this time.
What's this look like? When we multiply
that by millions of queries a day,
as you mentioned, each Xeon 6 plus
processor has up to 288 cores. That's
576 cores per two socket server. When we
look at that from a rack scale
perspective,
that gives us over 36,000 cores per 32
years of compute space.
>> Thank you, John. Wow, this is pretty
amazing. have some data to ponder on.
[applause]
By far the the density of CPU we showed
is is has the highest density per rack
ever. But also looking at the number of
agents and these are the new metrics
that are emerging, we can safely say
that that particular rack can run up to
150,000 agents. So good news to all the
CIOS in the audience. Now your very
expensive GPUs can be can see more
utilization because of uh our solutions.
Now both Zeon 6 with pores and ecores
are built on for intelligence at scale.
There are different cores of course but
we've seen the workloads that require
very high performance cores pushing the
frequencies but also there's a need for
very high density power efficient cores.
So we've seen all the workloads, we've
run all the analysis and we are
delivering these solutions uh to to all
of you.
Now
having said that we are working with our
customers and partners to make sure that
each solution is uh tailored to to your
needs. So
I'd like to welcome Libu back on stage
to talk about the server and rack sale
solutions that our partners are working
on. Thank you.
>> [applause]
>> Thank you my friend.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Uh thank you Kavoke. It is great to see
the momentum uh in the data center
as we look forward to see that is for
intelligence at scale. Discrete compute
alone is not enough. Our customer are
asking us to think of system level to
help them serve real agentic workloads
at scale. It push us to rethink how we
deliver our compute beyond the socket
and to the rack.
That is why we start the initiative
called Rex scale blueprints. [snorts]
Working with ecosystem partners to
develop Rex scale blueprints built on
open standards.
So customer can rapidly scale their
intelligent infrastructure with
confident without proprietary
workarounds.
Behind me as you can see two examples of
these blueprints. One is for agentic
performance based on Intel Xeon 6 with
pores.
The other is agent density with the
Intel Xeon 6 Plus with ECOS.
We are working closely with our partners
ecosystem including Foxcomanova
to expand our Rex scale offering. Let me
call on stage one of our partners, chief
product officer of Foxcom, Jerry Xiao to
talk about how we partners on Rick scale
solution.
[clears throat]
>> Thank you Libu. [applause]
Thank you, Jerry.
>> Um, I'm so excited to be here today.
Wonderful product and amazing event.
Jerry, Intel and Foxcom have been
working together to many decades and
Foxcom has been instrumental in driving
technology innovation in Taiwan and
around the world.
>> Yeah, that's right, Abu. Um I'm proud
the work we have done together from AI
servers to data centers
and to age computing all together and
today we're excited to announce the next
step in our partnership.
Intel and Fosscom are working together
to develop Rex scale products built upon
Intel Xeon processors. Together we will
focus on exploring the development
integrations and commercialization
of differentiated
uh rack scale AI infrastructure solution
leveraging comp complementaryary
architecture to address diverse AI
workload requirements.
Yeah, together we will continue to
deepen and expand our partnership
unlocking new opportunities ahead.
Through this collaboration, we will
deliver system level AI solution to our
joint customers in airballing more
integrated and scalable computing
environments. This makes it marks an
important step ahead and we look forward
unveiling more in the near future. Thank
you Liu.
>> Today is an exciting uh milestone for
our continual partnership uh with
Foxcom. Jerry, thank you for joining us.
>> Fantastic. Thank you for having me.
[applause]
Thank you to the many partners in the
audience today that is helping to bring
this rack scale vision to life providing
choice throughout uh through the
ecosystem power. Uh we do not believe
one size fit all approach for
intelligent centers. Each enterprise
will run unique workloads. So their
infrastructure needs will also need to
be unique and purpose-built. As you can
see from the screen here,
just look at the server in front of me.
Uh this is whole series of partnership
we have.
Intel is working with a lot of partners
to provide service racks scale solution
designed to fit your existing
infrastructure ready for AI at scale as
you can tell in front in front of you.
We see token usage exploding.
Agent now consume 1,000 time more tokens
than single event reasoning.
In addition to building the best CPUs,
it is critical that we deliver compute
solutions optimized for token
consumption and token generation.
The bottom line, AI at scale will
require hetogeneous computing. To this
end, Intel recently announced a
partnership with Sonova.
To talk more about this, let me call to
the stage founder CEO of Sambbernova,
Rodoro Leong.
Rodrigo, welcome to joining me today.
>> Thank you, Lupu. [clears throat]
>> And over the next few months, we have
announced few updates on our joint
development partnership. Can we talk a
little bit more about the work that
Intel and Sonova are doing together?
>> Absolutely. We've been busy. Earlier
this year, we announced a multi-year
collaboration to deliver high
performance, costefficient AI inference
solutions based on Xeon infrastructure.
We've been building something really
special. Excited to show you today.
This is the this is the SM50
sambar we announced earlier this year.
Rack scale AI infrastructure built for
agentic workloads.
>> [applause]
>> It uses Intel Xeon 6 processors with
Sonova SM50 RDUs and shipping to
customers later this year. Today, we're
also excited to demonstrate the world's
first heterogeneous disagregated
inference using Simonova's RDU with
Intel's CPU and Nvidia GPUs.
What you're about to see is the same
prompt, the same model running side by
side, two different stacks.
So the one on the left is GPUs, RDUs,
and CPUs. This aggregated difference in
difference. And this one on my right is
GPUs on their own. They both get the fed
the same prompt in the same model just
different stacks.
The disagregated inference stack is
taking off. And what's happening here is
you have the Xeon 6 processors doing all
the tooling execution. You have
Salmonova RDUs doing the decode and
generating all of the tokens. And then
you got the GPUs performing the PROM
caching and the faster prefill reducing
overall time.
When all three chips are working
together, you dramatically reduce the
end-to-end latency and the agents for
the fastest need for enentic AI and the
other side the GPU stack is still
working away.
So the initial result of our work is
disagregated inference is the the GPUs,
the RDUs, the CPUs that's the fastest
and artificial analysis and our test
found to be two to three times faster
than just the GPUs alone. And this gives
us an early look at how fast this can
be. Ro, the most exciting part about all
this is that we have tremendous customer
interest uh in these solutions.
>> Absolutely. So, let's see who comes
next. So, turn it back over to you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you. [applause]
To continue this conversation, I'm
delighted to invite my good friends uh
you know, Robert Smith uh is uh Vista
Equity Partners, chairman, CEO and and
uh you know of the partners and Roger
Smith to tell you more about how they
plan to use this racks from Intel and
Samanova. Robert.
>> Hey, thank you. [applause]
Lipu, good to see you.
>> Same here. Thank you so much for joining
me. Pleasure. Thank you. Thank you, my
friend. Thank you, my friend.
>> Yes. So, Robert, AI is driving huge
demand uh for computing and it is
reshaping the silicon system software
and at all at once. What are you seeing
and hearing from the enterprises that
you work with? Yeah, first of all, I'm
excited to be here at Computex to join
you at this wonderful event. Um, for us,
it's been quite quite incredible. Uh,
there's been a huge focus right now to
bring AI to enterprises around the
globe. Uh, we want to make it usable. We
want to make it impactful for the
organizations that we work with. You
know, we have over 90 portfolio
companies and well over half of them
have now uh have converted to Agentic
Solutions. And with over 750 million
users of our software, that really
translates to over 10 billion agents.
That's why we've launched Vector Core
Computer VC2 with our partners at
Cambium Capital to offer the world's
first commercially available
architecture for disagregated inference.
This novel agentic neocloud is built to
deliver the fastest enterprise inference
throughput of any architecture to date.
The demo you just witnessed with Rodrigo
was conducted live in our Los Angeles
data center and we have over 50
deployments planned in the US which are
targeted to convert existing data
centers to inference data centers. This
is very exciting and as we saw from Ro a
few minutes ago uh we are already
starting to see strong momentum for
these offerings. Can you talk a little
bit more about how Intel Victor core
compute and our partners like SANOVA are
bringing this aggregated uh inference to
life?
>> Of course uh I'm excited to share that
first together AI is the first
commercial customer uh and is excited to
use this architecture as a service to
accelerate inference workloads. We
expect many of our enterprise software
companies and their customers to quickly
follow as the demands for inference keep
growing and this is has to be and it is
more efficient than anything they pre
previously have had access to. Most
critically VC2 is built and utilizes the
Sabbanova stack which is an aircooled
data center. We believe it will deliver
what enterprise customers and
communities are asking for which is
reliable, low latency, lowcost inference
at scale. Partnering to advance AI is
one of the best ways to develop this
transformational technology making it
usable and economically viable for
enterprises worldwide.
>> Uh we are excited about that. Thank you
for joining me today and delighted to
have you here.
>> Always a pleasure, Liu. Thank you.
Congratulations. 14 more months. We're
excited to see what you're doing.
>> Thank you.
>> As you just saw from Ro and Robert,
picking the right silicon architecture
for your needs is critical for
enterprises today. There's a broad range
of architectures to choose from. As
large workloads increasingly become
strategic asset for companies, they are
increasingly looking for silicon built
around their exact needs.
Next, I would like to invite Sini, a
semiconductor design veteran and a
leader of our purpose-built silicon team
to talk more about the work we are doing
in this area. Swini
>> [applause]
[music]
>> Hi Leu, thank you. Thank you so much. A
very good afternoon to you guys.
Purpose-built silicon it is. This has
been a journey that the industry
industry has been using almost for the
last decade or so and especially
hyperscalers have tapped into this to
its full potential and shown us the
benefits in every way possible. Liu,
last year you challenged us to see in
this space given the fantastic assets
and the breadth of assets that we have
at Intel, how could we be relevant to
this? Not just be focused on the stuff
that we do internally. How do we bring
this out to the external world and do
something more? With that said, we we
had a proposition. We've been working on
it. And today I'm very happy to share a
couple of good outcomes that we have.
The first on the hyperscaler side we
have Google and Intel or Google and
Intel have gone into a partnership
wherein Intel is delivering what is
called as the infrastructure processing
unit. I would call it Intel processing
unit actually but infrastructure
processing unit which is a a piece of
silicon very vital for hyperscalers
performance and that journey continues
and by the way this is a deployment
today so it is not just something that
we are doing but it's already designed
and being deployed while this is this is
working on we've been Intel as a company
has been pretty active in the telco
market and in this telco market another
marquee customer Ericson has been uh
partnering with us and Ericson chooses
us wherein we deliver or Intel delivers
the next generation infrastructure
silicon for at a global scale for them
across the board. This just gives you a
very sneak preview at the highest level
to see the kind of work that's happening
in the purpose-built silicon space which
is a very exciting space and more
importantly a high growth space and I
was just thinking what better place than
Computex and Taipei where custom silicon
really is the name of the game here to
announce that Intel has officially
entered this market. So looking forward
to working with many of you guys and see
how we can be relevant to you some of
your aspirational goals on silicon.
Okay. Thank you Libu.
>> I'm super excited about all this
partnership that you announced and more
to come.
>> Yes, absolutely. More to come. Yes.
Thank you so much. Thank you so much
Libu. Thank you.
>> Thank you. [applause]
>> The work Sweeney and the team are doing
with purpose silicon is really
important. I'm super excited to be
partnering to build custom silicon with
many leading edge companies as well as
some of the most dynamic startups across
the industry vertical. I would like to
highlight some of this partnership
today.
One of the most exciting areas where we
can deploy advanced silicon is biomemed
engineering. For years, emulating the
function functionality of the human
brain has been the holy grail of
computing.
One company that is in the forefront of
brain inspire computing is echo neuro
technologies.
Let us hear more from Eddie Chan,
founder CEO of Echo Neuro Technology and
also one of the world best
neurosurgeons.
Hi, I'm Eddie Chang. I'm a neurosurgeon
at UCSF and co-founder of Echo
Neurochnologies.
For decades, AI has been brain inspired,
meaning borrowing ideas from
neuroscience at a distance. Neuromorphic
computing has carried that vision the
furthest. It built silicon around the
brain's core principles like spikes
sparse communication, memory, and
compute all in the same place. That
architecture is right. But what's been
missing is direct evidence of how the
brain actually performs the computation.
That's now within our reach. For the
first time, we can study how the human
cortex computes language in real time at
the resolution where computation
actually happens. This opens a whole new
possibility.
Algorithms that are not just brain
inspired, but new ones that are trained
on the brain activity itself, measured
against the brain itself. That's the
shift in our collaboration with Intel.
Together, we're developing brain trained
algorithms for streaming speech that
approach the efficiency of biological
computation.
The payoff runs both ways. AI that's
faster, lighter, and closer to how we
actually think, and new tools to restore
speech to people who have lost it.
Together with Intel, we're building AI
that learns from the most powerful
computer ever discovered, the human
brain. We're excited about what's ahead.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Eddie. I'm amazed by the work
you are doing. I'm confident that our
work together will help lay the
foundation of highly efficient AI
computers uh in the future.
Another company doing work at the
cutting edge of biology is Greenstone
Technologies.
We are partnering with Greenstone to
establish scalable reference
architectures
applicable across the broader life
imaging ecosystem.
Dr. Joseph Wu is the head of cardiology
at Stanford and the founder CEO of
Greenstone. Let's hear from him.
Hello, my name is Joseph Wu and I'm a
professor of medicine and director of
the Stanford Cardiovascular Institute as
well as the co-founder of Greenstone
Biosciences. Thank you so much for
including me in Computex. Intel and
Greenstone are working together to speed
up the development of new medicines. Our
partnership combines state-of-the-art
human genetics and biology from
Greenstone with advanced AI computing
for Intel so that we can scale data
processing, storage, and analysis.
Greenstone has built the world's largest
bio bank of human induced flu potent
stem cells. From just 10 cc's of your
blood, we can make your brain, heart,
liver, kidney, gut, and any type of
organoids in your body that are
genetically identical to the patient.
This will then allow us to test existing
and new medications more quickly and at
a lower cost. I believe the combination
of human biology and AI computing will
help shape the future of biio medicine
in the next decade. And this is why
we're so excited about the partnership
between Intel and Greenstone
Biosciences. Thank you very much and
enjoy the event. Shaja,
thank you Joe. I'm amazed by the work
you're doing and my excited about the
potential of our partnership.
Another key partners is Hitachi.
They have a wide range of capabilities
that help accelerating our our work our
plan around foundry tools and quantum
computing system. Let us hear from
Hitachi CEO Toko Nagasan.
>> Hello Computex. I'm Toshi Tokunaga, CEO
of Hitachi. For decades, Hitachi and
Intel have worked together to solve key
challenges for society. And today, we
are bringing our strength even closer.
By combining Intel's advanced computing
with Hitachi's industrial strength in
the physical world, we will create
intelligent solutions that will benefit
both businesses and society.
Thank you, Ibu. I look forward to our
future together.
>> Thank you, Titi.
We are really looking forward to working
with you.
Finally
uh if you look at you know we have the
brains inspire computing biomed medicine
and then energy. The last one is
industrial automation. Finally one
partner I would like to hear like you to
hear from is known for their pioneering
work in industrial automation. Let us
hear from my very good friend uh Rhoden
Bush at Seammens.
>> Hi Libu. As a customer of Intel, we all
know that global semiconductor demand
has hit a high record. In 2023, Seammens
and Intel already joined forces to meet
it. And now we are taking our
collaboration to the next level. We are
expanding our partnership across the
entire value chain from design to
manufacturing to chip applications in
seammen's products.
We improve design quality through EDA
automation and software solutions built
with Atlantic AI. We partner on all
areas of the manufacturing process
including product life cycle management,
automation, electrification, quality and
sustainability.
And what makes this even more relevant
for us, the chips created in this value
chain will be used in our own seammen's
products.
Looking forward to what's coming up.
>> Thank you, Roland.
>> [applause]
>> We are delighted to expand our long
partnership with the seaman groups.
I'm looking forward to disclose more
about this partnership in the coming
months and we are working with several
other partners to keep pushing the
boundary of what is possible.
I would like to close by returning to
where we start our conversation.
The opportunity for Intel and for our
partners is immersed PC edge agentic
physical AI data center and emerging
intelligence center from silicon to SOC
to system and applications.
This opportunity
is only made possible by all of you.
Look at the list and the largest
ecosystem of partners, suppliers and
customer.
Intel is an iconic company. We lay the
foundation of modern-day computing and
we are proud of our heritage.
But we do not want to rest on our honors
and gora. A year ago, I joined as a CEO.
I challenged my team to work with me to
build a new Intel.
That is exactly what we are doing. We
are not encumbent by the past. We are
building something wonderful.
It is had been year of transformation
for Intel. We ram our 18A to high volume
with multiple products. We are executing
well on our advanced packaging
milestones. We make tremendous progress
on engaging customers and building our
foundry business. We introduce new SOC's
for all major compute platforms from
premium mobile to high density cloud and
5G.
We are be rebuilding and strengthening
partnership across the ecosystem.
where I double down on creating new
business opportunity
across existing and emerging domains.
We are working at the forefront to
imagine re-imagine computing and make it
highly efficient for the AI era.
And this is just the beginning. I super
excited to continue executing at hypers
speed.
>> Before the lights go out,
the race begins.
From simulation to strategy, performance
begins with compute. With electrons that
power pace and data that backs
decisions,
the race never ends. Engineering never
stops.
Intel, official compute partner with
McLaren Racing.